Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations WEB.ARC.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Prison Activist Resource Center Archived Website, Sep 2, 2009- ongoing; Prison Activist Resource Center.
  Prison Activist Resource Center (PARC) is a prison abolitionist group that works to expose institutionalized racism, sexism, able-ism, heterosexism, and classism within the Prison Industrial Complex (PIC). PARC works to build strategies to build safety in communities without reliance on law enforcement and PIC. PARC also works to expose prisoner neglect and/or torture of people imprisoned in the United States, support a moratorium on prison construction, and build awareness of prison issues outside of the United States.
- Prisoner Solidarity Archived Website, Mar 5, 2012-Sep 5, 2013; Prisoner Solidarity
  Prisoner Solidarity operates as a communication tool between prisoners and people on the outside. It publishes updated research, news, opinion pieces and educational material from activists, writers, prisoners, and the concerned public. The website contains a newsletter, news updates, and a page on the 1993 Lucasville Uprising.
  Lucasville (Ohio); Prison riots |z United States.; Prisoners |x Civil rights |z United States.
- Prison Radio Archived Website, Mar 7, 2012- ongoing; Prison Radio
  Prison Radio is a radio and activist project that produces the commentaries of several prisoners, including Mumia Abu-Jamal. The project's political aims include analyzing the prison-industrial complex and attempting to present a more humanistic view of prisoners to the public. The website contains a multimedia page, a news page, and a blog.
  Abu-Jamal, Mumia; Alternative radio broadcasting.; Prisoners |x Civil rights.
- Privacy SOS Archived Website, Jul 18, 2013- ongoing; American Civil Liberties Union of Massachusetts
  PrivacySOS.org, a project of the American Civil Liberties Union of Massachusetts, works to combat the rise of surveillance technology after the attacks on September 11, 2001 and provide information on actions to take to protect individual privacy. The website contains a blog, their "Surveillance in the Age of Total Information Awareness" report, resources to protect privacy, and information on the different types of surveillance used by the United States government.
  Privacy, Right of |z United States.; September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001--Political aspects--United States.
- Private Manning Support Network Archived Website, Oct 18, 2013- ongoing; Private Manning Support Network
  The Private Manning Support Network is an organization dedicated to freeing Private Chelsea (formerly Bradley) Manning from serving a 35 year prison sentence for providing classified information to WikiLeaks. In August 2013, the organization changed its name when Manning announced she would like to begin to be known publicly by the name of Chelsea Elizabeth Manning, pursue hormone therapy, and be referred to with female pronouns. The organization raises funds for Manning, posts news about Manning and on other cases related to government surveillance and whistle-blowing, as well as a campaign to pardon Manning. The website also contains a significant amount of information on the trial that took place in 2013.
- Progressive Caucus of the California Democratic Party Archived Website, May 11, 2012- ongoing; Progressive Caucus of the California Democratic Party
  The Progressive Caucus of the California Democratic Party works to reform the Democratic Party and promote social justice. The website contains information on regions, multimedia, events, foreign policy, legislative policy, a calendar, and a blog.
  Democratic Party (U.S.).
- ProgressiveCongress.org Archived Website, Jun 9, 2010- ongoing; ProgressiveCongress.org
  Progressive Congress was founded in 1992 by the Congressional Progressive Caucus (CPC) and leaders in the progressive movement. The Progressive Congress focuses its efforts around four key policy areas, peace and global security, energy independence and environmental sustainability; civil rights, civil liberties, and human rights; and public health, education and economic opportunity. Progressive Map is the Wiki page of Progressive Congress.
  Political action committees |z United States.; Political participation |z United States.; Progressivism (United States politics).; United States. Congress.
- Progressive Democrats of America Archived Website, Feb 26, 2010- ongoing; Progressive Democrats of America
  The Progressive Democrats of America (PDA), founded in 2004, is a progressive political organization and grassroots political action committee (PAC) operating inside the United States Democratic Party. PDA action priorities have included an end to the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, Medicare for all, voters rights, healthcare reform, and economic and environmental justice.
  Democratic Party (U.S.).; Liberalism |z United States; Progressivism (United States politics).
- Progressive Jewish Alliance Archived Website, Jul 30, 2009-Mar 18, 2012; PJA: Progressive Jewish Alliance.
  The Progressive Jewish Alliance (PJA) was founded in 1999 by Jewish (Los) Angelenos seeking to assert a progressive Jewish presence in the campaigns for economic and social justice in Southern California, including campaigning for improved working conditions for low wage workers, to reform the criminal justice system, and to promote tolerance by facilitating Muslim-Jewish dialogue. PJA merged with the Jewish Funds for Justice in 2011. For newer crawls, please see Progressive Jewish Alliance (PJA) and Jewish Funds for Justice captures.
  Jew |x Identity |z United States.; Jewish radicals |z United States.; Jews |x Political activity |z United States.
- Progressive Labor Party Archived Website, Jul 29, 2009- ongoing; Progressive Labor Party.
  The Progressive Labor Party (PLP), established in 1962, is a militant communist faction that works to eliminate capitalism and institute communism through a revolutionary movement and a mass Red Army. PLP organizes workers, students and soldiers to turn capitalism driven wars into a revolution for communism. The website contains issues of its newspaper, Challenge, multimedia, news postings and analysis, a history of the party, and a blog.
  Communism |z United States.
- ProgressiveMap: A Project of ProgrssiveCongress.org Archived Website, Jun 11, 2010-Jun 15, 2012; ProgressiveCongress.org
  Created by ProgressiveCongress.org, theProgressiveMap.com is a wiki for collaboration within and outside of Congress in the progressive movement.
  Political participation |z United States.; Progressivism (United States politics) |v Encyclopedias and dictionaries.; United States. Congress.
- Progressive Portal Archived Website, Jan 7, 2011- ongoing; Progressive Portal
  Progressive Portal, founded in 2001, is an independent grassroots organization that works on a range of progressive issues and promotes increased activism through letter writing and other simple online activism.
  Human rights; Political participation; Social justice.; Web portals.
- Progressive Radio Network Archived Website, Aug 17, 2009- ongoing; Progressive Radio Network.
  Progressive Radio Network (PRN) is an independent, listener supported station that focuses on distributing content on topics such as health, news, politics, art, culture, women’s issues, and other issues. Some broadcasters on PRN include Gary Null, Jim Garrison, Michio Kaku, Jim Hightower, Greg Palast, Caryn Hartglass, Mitch Rabin, Michael Toms, Danny Schacter, Richard Martin, James Turner as well as the weekly radio programs of The Nation Magazine (Radio Nation with Laura Flanders), Global Research News Hour, The Wisdom Forum, Free Speech Radio News and many more.
- Project Censored Archived Website, May 15, 2012- ongoing; Project Censored
  Project Censored, founded in 1976 by Carl Jensen, is an investigative journalism and media criticism project. The website works to publish news left unpublished by the mainstream media and raise awareness of censorship of news and media accountability. Project Censored highlights independent news sources and has a weekly radio show. The website contains news, investigative research and reporting, an events page, and a blog, called the Censored Notebook.
  Mass media criticism.
- Project South Archived Website, Jul 17, 2012- ongoing; Project South
  Project South is a Southern-based leadership development organization that uses popular education, partnership and alliances, and organizing to build political, educational, and economic power at the grassroots of low-income communities. The website contains information on their current projects and programs.
- ProLibertad Freedom Campaign Archived Website, Sep 28, 2007-Oct 14, 2011; ProLibertad Freedom Campaign.
  ProLibertad Freedom Campaign was a support website for the Puerto Rican nationalists who were imprisoned in the United States for sedition in the early 1980s and Puerto Rican political prisoners in general. The organization worked to release the prisoners, eleven of which were offered clemency in 1999 by President Bill Clinton. As of 2013, one prisoner, Oscar López Rivera, remains in prisoner. The website was defunct by late 2011, at that point two other prisoners, Avelino Gonzalez Claudio, and Norberto Gonzalez Claudio, also remained in prison. It contains writings by the prisoners, a radio show, newsletters, video, and a history of the organization and cases.
  Political prisoners |z United States.; Prisoners |x Civil rights.; Puerto Rico.
- Prometheus Radio Project Archived Website, Mar 6, 2010- ongoing; Prometheus Radio Project
  The Prometheus Radio Project founded in 1998, builds, supports, and advocates community radio stations and works to empower community voices and movements for social change. Prometheus Radio Project supports community groups at every stage of the process, including the technology of building community radio stations, facilitate public participation in the FCC regulatory process, and sponsor events promoting awareness and support of media democracy and LPFM (low-power FM) radio.
  Alternative radio broadcasting; Community radio; Low power radio.
- PR Watch Archived Website, Aug 2, 2009- ongoing; Center for Media and Democracy (Madison, Wis.)
  PR Watch is the Center for Media and Democracy’s online magazine. Established in 1993 by John Stauber, CMD’s mission is to promote transparency and an informed debate by exposing corporate spin and government propaganda and by engaging the public in collaborative, fair and accurate reporting and analysis. CMD has been publishing PRWatch since 1994 and transitioned from print subscription to online publication in 2008. They also sponsor "open content" media to enable citizens to participate in creating media content.
  Mass media |z United States.; Transparency--United States.
- Public Citizen Archived Website, Apr 17, 2010- ongoing; Public Citizen
  Public Citizen, founded in 1971, is a political advocacy group that works to represent all citizens in Washington D.C. in U.S. Congress, the executive branch, and the courts. Public Citizen has worked to challenge the practices the pharmaceutical, nuclear and automobile industries, and mega-corporations. Public Citizen is a nonprofit organization that does not participate in partisan political activities or endorse any candidates for elected office. Public Citizen initiatives include Congress Watch, the Energy Program, Global Trade Watch division, the Health Research Group and the Litigation Group
  Anti-globalization movement.; Consumer protection.; Lobbyists.; Public health.
- Puerto Rico - Solidarity Network / Red Solidaria PR-SN Archived Website, Jul 7, 2011-Oct 7, 2012; Puerto Rico Solidarity Network
  The Puerto Rico Solidarity Network is an organization that works to inform and build support for the Puerto Rico working class labor, community, environment, and student grassroots struggles and also work to promote and develop connections in New York and across the United States.
  Puerto Rico--History--Autonomy and independence movements; Working class--Puerto Rico
- Queer/LGBTIQA2Z Caucus at Occupy Wall Street Archived Website, Jun 28, 2013- ongoing; Queer/LGBTIQA2Z Caucus at Occupy Wall Street
  The Queer/LGBTIQA2Z Caucus is a caucus within the Occupy Wall Street Movement that works to empower people of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, intersex, queer, asexual, two-spirited, and gender neutral orientation and their allies. The group provides a forum to discuss queer issues and educate people of queer culture and concepts. The website contains event listings and news on the group.
  Gay rights movement.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- QuestionCopyright.org Archived Website, May 10, 2011- ongoing; questioncopyright.org
  QuestionCopyright.org, founded in 2007, that works to expand the range of acceptable public debate about copyright and reframe the way artists and other look at copyright. The website supports programs that highlight the restrictive effects of distribution monopolies, and help creators and their allies realize the potential of freedom-based distribution and do not equate copying with theft, with plagiarism, or the abuse or destruction of the original work. The website promotes actions through video, art project, and other campaigns.
  Anti-copyright movement.; Copyright
- R.A. Forum > Research on Anarchism Archived Website, Aug 21, 2009- ongoing; R.A. Forum / Research on Anarchism
  R.A. Forum / Research on Anarchism (English language site) principally consists of articles, mainly scholarly, on all aspects of anarchism, including its worldwide history, with an interdisciplinary perspective. It also contains news, audio (talks and music), and films/DVDs.
  Anarchism |v Sources.; Anarchism.
- Radical Art Caucus Archived Website, Nov 4, 2009-Nov 3, 2012; Radical Art Caucus
  The Radical Art Caucus’ (RAC) primary mission is the promotion of art and art historical scholarship that addresses problems of oppression and possibilities for resistance. RAC seeks to provide an intellectual and professional environment for the discussion of labor and social justice issues specifically related to contemporary practices of art and art history.
  Art historians |z United States.; Art |x Political aspects.
- Radical History Review Archived Website, Mar 27, 2014-ongoing; Radical History Review.
  The Mid-Atlantic Radical Historians Organization (MARHO) was formed during a conference at Fordham University in January 1973, attended mostly by professors at colleges and universities in the metropolitan New York area. he journal seeks to "address issues of gender, race, sexuality, imperialism, and class" and stretch "the boundaries of historical analysis to explore Western and non-Western histories." In addition to articles on the theme of any given issue, the journal is often comprised of sections dedicated to teaching and public history, as well as reviews of television, books, museum exhibitions, and other media. The website contains call for proposals for future issues, descriptions of recent issues, subject guides, and back issues.
  MARHO (Organization).; New Left |z United States |v Periodicals.; New Left |z United States.; Radicalism |z United States.; United States |x History |v Periodicals.
- Radical Homosexual Agenda Archived Website, Aug 2, 2009 - Nov 2, 2012; Radical Homosexual Agenda.
  The Radical Homosexual Agenda is a contingent of New York City LGBTQ community that work to gain rights beyond marriage. RHA works for affordable housing and healthcare, an end to war and the prison industrial complex. The website contains action alerts and has been inactive since 2009.
  Gay rights |z New York (State) |z New York.; Sexual minorities |z United States.
- Radical Philosophy Association Archived Website, Nov 29, 2008 - ongoing; Radical Philosophy Association.
  Founded in 1982, the Radical Philosophy Association is an international organization whose members struggle against capitalism, racism, sexism, homophobia, disability discrimination, environmental ruin, and all other forms of domination, drawing upon a variety of radical traditions including phenomenology, Marxism, anarchism, post-structuralism, post-colonial theory and environmentalism. Its efforts center on conferences and publications. The RPA also publishes the journal Radical Philosophy Review.
  Philosophers |x Political activity.
- Radical Reference Archived Website, Nov 26, 2008 - ongoing; Radical Reference
  Radical Reference, launched in 2004, is a collective of library workers that support activist communities, progressive organizations, and independent journalists by providing professional research support, education, and access to information. The website provides reference to activists and independent journalists related to their activities.
  Librarians--Political activity--United States.; Reference and research services--United States.
- Radical Women Archived Website, Dec 9, 2011- ongoing; Radical Women.
  Radical Women (RW) is a socialist feminist, grassroots activist organization that provides a radical voice within the feminist movement and trains women to be leaders in the movements for social and economic justice. The organization promotes union action and international solidarity, combats racism in the women's movement and views capitalism as part of the reason why women are oppressed. Radical Women was founded in 1967 by Gloria Martin. It is affiliated with the Freedom Socialist Party (FSP). The website contains event notices and activities.
- Radios Populares Archived Website, Oct 12, 2011- ongoing; Radios Populares
  Radios Populares (RaPo), founded in 2002, is a Chicago-based collective that collaborates with communities working for social justice to build low-power FM community radio stations. Their work is grounded in a solidarity model which builds alliances between Radios Populares, media activists, and community organizations of the social justice movement. The radio collective also works for media justice and community control over media content.
  Alternative radio broadcasting.; Low power radio.
- Reaching Critical Will Archived Website, Mar 6, 2012- ongoing; Women's International League for Peace and Freedom.
  Reaching Critical Will, created in 1999, is a project of the Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (WILPF) that works for complete disarmament, the abolition of nuclear weapons, the reduction of global military spending, and demilitarization of politics and society. Reaching Critical Will was designed to increase the quality and quantity of NGO preparation and participation in UN disarmament processes and of NGO interaction with governments and the United Nations; to provide logistical support in facilitating activities during relevant conferences tailored for policy-makers and the public; and to provide accurate and timely reporting on all relevant conferences and initiatives so that those unable to attend can stay informed. The website contains information on conferences and assemblies, the non-proliferation treaty, publications, news, action alerts, and contacts.
  Nuclear disarmament.; Women and peace.
- Real Cost of Prisons Project Archived Website, Mar 3, 2012- ongoing; The Real Cost of Prisons Project
  The Real Cost of Prisons, started in 2000, seeks to broaden and deepen the organizing capacity of prison/justice activists working to end mass incarceration. The Real Cost of Prisons Project brings together justice activists, artists, justice policy researchers and people directly experiencing the impact of mass incarceration to create popular education materials and other resources which explore the immediate and long-term costs of incarceration on the individual, community, and the nation level. The website contains a blog, pages on different types of media, including comic books, videos, music, and other writings.
  Imprisonment |x Economic aspects |z United States.
- Rebuild the Dream Archived Website, Jan 8, 2012- ongoing; Rebuild the Dream
  Rebuild the Dream uses current technology and media to mobilize, organize, and broaden the base of people working to fix America’s economy and "defend the American Dream." The website contains a list of proposed economic solutions, a video page and teach-in materials.
  Distributive justice.; Job creation.; Social justice.
- Redstockings: Women's Liberation Studies Archives for Action Archived Website, Nov 10, 2009- ongoing; Redstockings, Inc.
  Redstockings was a name taken in 1969 by one of the founding women's liberation groups of the 1960's to represent the union of two traditions: the "bluestocking" label disparagingly pinned on feminists of earlier centuries--and "red" for revolution. Redstockings today is a grassroots, activist "think tank", for defending and advancing the women's liberation agenda. The Archives for Action is a project Redstockings established in 1989 to make the experiences of the 1960’s movement more widely available for new understandings and improved strategies. The movement also supports a national health care system and equal job benefits for women.
  Feminism |z United States |x History |y 20th century.; Redstockings.
- Red Wedge Magazine Archived Website, Apr 26, 2013- ongoing; Red Wedge Magazine
  Red Wedge Magazine, which published its first issue in August 2012, is an arts and cultural publication written and edited by revolutionary Marxist activists, artists and cultural workers. The magazine focuses on art from the socialist perspective, and includes writings on topics such as solidarity, internationalism, feminism, sexual liberation, anti-racism, and workers’ self-emancipation. The magazine explores the connection of art and culture to economic and political issues. They publish articles on theoretical and historical currents of art, reviews, commentary, and audio-visual materials. The website contains issues of the magazine, articles, and other media.
  Art |x Economic aspects |z United States.; Art |x Political aspects |z United States.; Socialism and art.; Socialism |z United States |v Periodicals.
- Refuse & Resist! Archived Website, Mar 27, 2014; Refuse & Resist! (Organization).
  Refuse & Resist! was a human rights activist group founded in New York City in 1987. They opposed censorship, war, acts of police brutality, advocated against the death penalty and other acts of violence. They supported political prisoners, undocumented immigrants, the poor, and reproductive rights. Refuse & Resist! worked through nonviolent resistance, including speaking out in schools, communities and in the media; organizing forums and meetings; demonstrating in the streets; creating and performing cultural works; and contributing financially. The organization officially dissolved in 2006 and the website ceased updating in 2008. The website contains news listings, their CounterAttack magazine, and their artists network.
  Human rights |z United States.; Peace movements |z United States.; Prisoners |x Civil rights |z United States.; Radicals |z United States |x Civil rights.
- Religion and Socialism Commission Archived Website, May 4, 2012-Feb 3, 2014; Religion and Socialism Commission
  Religion and Socialism, first published in 1977, is the biannual publication of the Religious Socialists. The Religious Socialists are part of the Democratic Socialists of America (DSA) and the organization is open to DSA members of all faiths whose socialism is in some way inspired by their spiritual identity. The website contains issues of their publication.
  Socialism and religion
- Reprieve Archived Website, Jun 2, 2011- ongoing; Reprieve.